Robotics students often memorize transformations
without seeing what the symbols do.
AxisLab turns equations into verified lessons
where students predict, manipulate, observe, and check.
Six modules connect robot motion,
coordinate systems, orientation, velocity, and forces.
The direct robot demonstration is deterministic
and requires no external model call.
Changing d1 translates along its joint axis,
while theta2 rotates the downstream chain.
The 3D model, DH table, matrices,
and end-effector position update together.
The RPY and Euler wrist can be rotated with the mouse
and controlled with three live angle sliders.
Learners compare rotation conventions,
recover inverse angles, and inspect singularities.
Coordinate, Jacobian, trajectory, and dynamics labs
use the same active-learning interface.
Each lesson combines visible geometry,
equations, controls, and scored questions.
Natural-language questions can request
a customized advanced robotics lesson.
The model proposes teaching intent,
difficulty, and bounded starting parameters.
Deterministic code validates the result
and owns numerical answers and scoring.
Generated code is never executed,
and provider failures activate reviewed fallback lessons.
Codex helped analyze the system,
plan the architecture, and implement the learning modules.
It supported mathematical review, automated tests,
responsive design, debugging, and deployment migration.
[Replace this subtitle with the exact, verified way
GPT-5.6 contributed to the final project.]
Twenty-one backend tests and twenty frontend tests
verify the current implementation.
The public HTTPS demo requires no account,
and direct lessons remain available without an AI provider.
AxisLab makes difficult robotics mathematics
visible, interactive, and verifiable.
It is a safer foundation for active,
AI-assisted robotics education.